Ehsanur Rahman Rhythm

STUDENT

Dhaka, Bangladesh

\$\cup +8801779092201 | \$\subseteq\$ ehsanur.rahman.rhythm@g.bracu.ac.bd | \$\mathbf{n}\$ errhythm.me | \$\mathbf{o}\$ errhythm | \$

Summary_

I am Ehsanur Rahman Rhythm, a dedicated and hardworking computer science student currently studying at Brac University in Dhaka, Bangladesh. I am a self-taught developer who has honed my skills in website development over the past 7 years, including proficiency in HTML, CSS, and CMS systems such as Wordpress, Xenforo, Magento, and Opencart. Additionally, I am experienced in Javascript and have created Discord bots using Node.js.

Furthermore, my interest in data science and natural language processing (NLP) has led me to publish research papers in IEEE. I am constantly seeking opportunities to expand my knowledge and skills in these fields and am excited to continue my journey in the field of computer science.

Education

Brac University

Dhaka, Bangladesh

B.Sc. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Jan. 2020 -

Work Experience _____

Shromik Dhaka, Banqladesh

LEAD WEB DEVELOPER Aug. 2021 - May. 2022

- Developed the news portal website with WordPress.
- Optimized website performance with a GTmetrix grade of A. (99% performance score)

HardPixel TV Sports

Dhaka, Bangladesh

LEAD WEB DEVELOPER Jan. 2021 - Nov. 2021

- Developed their Sports Infotainment website with WordPress and WPBakery.
- Collaborated with the Design Team to enhance the visual appeal of the website by implementing new designs, color schemes, and layouts, which improved the overall user experience.
- · Implemented new features such as Live Score viewer and Dark Mode, which increased the website's functionality and attracted more users.

bdnews24.comDhaka, Bangladesh

CHILD JOURNALIST Apr. 2013 - Jun. 2017

- Selected as a Child Journalist in collaboration between bdnews24.com and UNICEF, reporting on children's rights and welfare.
- · Gained valuable skills in journalism, research, and writing, and raised awareness about important issues facing children in my community.
- Developed understanding of the role of media in shaping public opinion and its impact on society.

Game Liberation '71 Dhaka, Bangladesh

May. 2013 - Dec. 2015

WEB DEVELOPER

- Developed the Official Website of Liberation '71 with WordPress.
- · Collaborated with the designers to improve the design of the site.
- Worked with the Game Programming Team and also helped in beta testing.

Honors & Awards

2018 **Champion**, Mikko Foundation Design Competition Winner

2018 Champion, DIF18 Best Presentation Award

Skills_

Programming Languages Python, JavaScript, NodeJS, Java, HTML, CSS

Data Science and ML Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scikit-learn, PyTorch

Database Management MySQL, MongoDB **Operating System** Windows, Linux

Website CMS Wordpress, Woocommerce, Xenforo, OpenCart, PrestaShop, Weebly

Softwares & Tools Visual Studio Code, PyCharm, Microsoft Office, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Premiere Pro

| Publications . |
|-----------------------|
|-----------------------|

Bengali Speech Recognition: An Overview

IICAIET

Mashuk Arefin Pranjol, Farhin Rahman, **Ehsanur Rahman Rhythm**, Rajvir Ahmed Shuvo, Tanjib Ahmed, Bushra Yesmeen Anika, Md. Abdullah Al Masum Anas, Jahidul Hasan, Saiadul Arfain, Shadab Iqbal, Md Humaion Kabir Mehedi. Annajiat Alim Rasel

2022

Sentiment Analysis of Restaurant Reviews from Bangladeshi Food Delivery Apps

To be published

EHSANUR RAHMAN RHYTHM, RAJVIR AHMED SHUVO, MD SABBIR HOSSAIN, MD. FARHADUL ISLAM AND ANNAJIAT ALIM RASEL

2023

Distributed Computing for Big Data Analytics: Challenges and Opportunities

To be published

EHSANUR RAHMAN RHYTHM, RAJVIR AHMED SHUVO, MD HUMAION KABIR MEHEDI, MD SABBIR HOSSAIN AND ANNAJIAT ALIM RASEL

2023

Predicting Taxi Fares in New York City using XGBoost and LightGBM

To be published

EHSANUR RAHMAN RHYTHM, RAJVIR AHMED SHUVO, S.M.AZWAD-UL-ALAM AND SIFAT E JAHAN

2023

Projects

FacultyPedia

PHP, MySQL, TAILWIND CSS

Aug. 2022

- An anonymous review system for students
- Ability to schedule a consultation hour with the faculty

Class Reminder Bot

NODEJS

Jun 2021

- Discord Bot which will send you a message 10 minutes before your class
- · Ability to add Google Meet/Zoom link in reminder message

Discord TaskBot

NodeJS

Mar. 2021

- Discord Bot which will let you add various task with deadlines
- Lets you see your deadlines in a specific channel

Extracurricular Activity

BNMPC IT Club

Dhaka, Bangladesh

SECRETARY OF PROGRAMMING & WEB DEVELOPMENT

Sep. 2017 - Aug. 2019

- · Volunteered as a founding member in BNMPC IT Club with a goal to introduce the college students about fast growing technology.
- Developed the official website of the then BNMPC IT Club.
- Taught many students about the basic of Web Development.